Hey everyone, and welcome!
みなさん、こんにちは！
Ever find yourself wanting to say no in English, but you're not 100% sure how.
英語で「ノー」と言いたいけど、どう言えばいいか分からないことはありませんか？
It's one of those super important skills, but it has a couple of little tricks, so let's
これはとても重要なスキルですが、いくつかのコツがあります。
dive in and finally master how to make negative sentences.
さあ、ネガティブな文の作り方をマスターしましょう。
Alright, let's start with the simple, positive sentence that I think pretty much all of
まずは、みんなが共感できるシンプルな肯定文から始めましょう。「私はコーヒーが好きです。」
us can get behind. I like coffee.
明確で直接的です。これが今日の出発点です。
It's clear, it's direct, and it's going to be our starting point for today.
でも、コーヒーが嫌いな人はどう言えばいいのでしょう？
But what if you're one of those people who, I don't know, doesn't like coffee?
反対のことをどう言いますか？
How do you say the opposite?
ただ「not」を入れるだけではダメです。
You can't just stick the word not in there somewhere. Or can you?
それが今解決する大きな問題です。
Well, that's the big question we're going to solve right now.
このパズルを解くために少し助けが必要です。
Okay, so to solve this puzzle, we're going to need a little bit of help.
私たちの新しい親友は「do not」というフレーズです。
And our new best friend is this phrase right here, do not.
これはネガティブな文を作るための魔法の鍵です。
This is the magic key that unlocks negative sentences, especially when we're talking
特に行動について話すときに使います。
about actions. So how does this actually work? It's super simple.
では、実際にどうやって使うのでしょうか？とても簡単です。
Check it out. You start with your positive sentence, right?
まずは肯定文から始めます。
I play soccer.
「私はサッカーをします。」
When you just drop our helper, do not, right before the action verb, play.
その後、動詞の前に「do not」を入れます。
So you get, I do not play soccer.
そうすると「私はサッカーをしません。」になります。
And of course, in everyday conversations, you'll almost always hear the shortcut, I don't
日常会話では「I don't play soccer」と短縮して言うことがほとんどです。
play soccer. See? Easy.
簡単ですね。
Okay, so you might be thinking, why all the fuss?
でも、なぜこんなに複雑に感じるのでしょうか？
Why can't I just throw the word not in there?
「not」を入れるだけではダメなのはなぜですか？
And that is a great question.
それは良い質問です。
This is where things get a little tricky for a lot of learners, because in English we
ここで多くの学習者がつまずくポイントがあります。
actually have two different kinds of verbs that follow two different rules.
英語には異なるルールに従う2種類の動詞があります。
And this slide right here shows you exactly why.
このスライドがその理由を示しています。
On the left, you've got your B verbs. You know, am, is, are.
左側には「B動詞」があります。am、is、areです。
With these guys, it's easy. You just add not after them.
これらは簡単で、後に「not」を付けるだけです。
I am hungry becomes I am not hungry. But look at the right side.
「I am hungry」は「I am not hungry」になります。右側を見てみましょう。
For action verbs, things you do, like like or play, that's when you need our helper
行動を表す動詞、例えば「like」や「play」では、動詞の前に「do not」を入れる必要があります。
do not to go before the verb. The big takeaway?
重要なポイントは、まず動詞の種類を見極めることです。
You have to figure out what kind of verb you're working with first.
これで基本ルールは理解できましたね。
Alright, you've totally got the main rule down. Well one, complete.
でも、少しだけ特別なルールがあります。
But there's a little twist.
それは「he」「she」「it」の場合です。
A special rule that only applies when we're talking about he, she, or it.
通常の肯定文では、主語が「he」「she」「it」のとき、動詞の末尾にSを付けます。
So in a normal positive sentence, when your subject is he, she, or it, you usually add
「he live in Paris」ではなく「he lives in Paris」と言います。
an S to the end of the action verb.
そのSに注目してください。
You don't say he live in Paris, you say he lives in Paris.
文を否定形にすると、そのSが「do」の前に移動して「does」になります。
Now keep a close eye on that S, because it's about to do something pretty cool.
そうすると「he does not live in Paris」になります。
And here's the magic trick.
ここで重要なのは、動詞「live」は元の形に戻ることです。
When we make the sentence negative, that little s from lives actually hops over to our helper
そのSは移動するだけで、コピーされるわけではありません。
word do, and it turns it into does.
「he does not lives」は間違いです。
So we get, he does not live in Paris.
さて、話はここまでにしましょう。
The super important thing to remember here is that the verb live goes back to its original
理論は一つのことですが、実践が大切です。
form. That s moves, it doesn't get copied.
では、少し練習しましょう。
So saying he does not lives, nope, that's a common mistake, but it's incorrect.
いくつかの文を出しますので、正しく言えるか試してみてください。準備はいいですか？
Okay, enough talk, right?
では、最初の文です。「彼らはホラー映画が好きです。」
Theory is one thing, but practice is where it really sticks.
これを否定形にするとどうなりますか？
So let's do a quick tune up. I'm gonna throw a few sentences at you,
考える時間をどうぞ。さあ、答えはこれです。
see if you can get them right. You ready?
「彼らはホラー映画が好きではありません。」
Okay, first one, they like horror movies.
友達と話しているときは「they don't like horror movies」と言います。
How do you flip that into a negative?
主語は「they」です。
Go on, take a second to think about it. And boom, there it is.
だから、標準の「do not」ルールを使います。できましたね。
They do not like horror movies.
では、もう少し難しくしてみましょう。
Or if you're just chatting with friends,
「スーは日曜日にテニスをします。」
they don't like horror movies. The subject is they.
どのように否定形にしますか？
Is not, do not, or does not? Think carefully.
「Is not」「do not」「does not」のどれ？ よく考えてみて。
The winner is does not. And why is that?
正解は「does not」です。なぜでしょう？
Well, Sue is just like saying she, right?
Sueは「彼女」と同じですからね。
And that triggers our special third-person rule.
これが特別な三人称のルールを引き起こします。
Since play is an action verb, we need does not. Awesome.
「play」は動作動詞なので、「does not」が必要です。素晴らしい。
Okay, last challenge.
さて、最後のチャレンジです。
This one is to make sure everything is clicked into place.
これはすべてが正しく整っているか確認するためです。
He from New Zealand. What's the right choice here?
「He from New Zealand」。正しい選択は？
Really think about the verb that would be in the original sentence.
元の文にある動詞をよく考えてみてください。
And the answer is, is not. Ha, did we catch you?
答えは「is not」です。あれ、引っかかりましたか？
This was a little test.
これはちょっとしたテストでした。
The full positive sentence would be he is from New Zealand.
完全な肯定文は「he is from New Zealand」です。
The verb is is, that's a B verb. And what's our rule for B verbs?
動詞は「is」で、これはB動詞です。B動詞のルールは？
We just stick not right after it. You guys are nailing this.
その後に「not」を付けるだけです。みんな素晴らしいです。
Wow, you did an absolutely amazing job.
わあ、素晴らしい仕事をしましたね。
We've gone through the main rule, the beaver of exception,
主要なルール、例外のB動詞、
and that tricky third-person twist.
そして難しい三人称のひねりを学びました。
So let's wrap it all up in a handy little cheat sheet
では、便利なチートシートにまとめましょう。
you can use anytime you need it. And here it is, your go-to guide.
いつでも使えるガイドです。こちらがそのガイドです。
This table breaks it all down.
この表で全てを整理しています。
All you have to do is ask yourself two simple questions.
自分に二つの簡単な質問をするだけです。
First, who's the subject? And second, what kind of verb is it?
まず、主語は誰か？次に、動詞は何か？
The answer tells you exactly what to do.
答えが何をすべきか教えてくれます。
Use do not, does not, or just a plain old not.
「do not」「does not」、またはただの「not」を使います。
That's the whole system right there on one screen.
これが一つの画面にまとめた全システムです。
So there you have it, you are now officially equipped
これで、あなたは自信を持って 英語で「ノー」と言えるようになりました。
to say no confidently in English. You can disagree with someone,
誰かに反対したり、 嫌なことを伝えたり、情報を訂正したりできます。
you can state what you don't like, you can correct information,
これは本当に強力なスキルです。
And that just leaves us with one last thing to think about.
最後に考えるべきことが一つ残っています。
Now that you know how to say no,
「ノー」と言えるようになった今、
what are you gonna say yes to learning next?
次に何を学ぶことに「イエス」と言いますか？
Thanks so much for joining me.
参加してくれてありがとう。